[
    {
        "question": "Field trips are useful to understand the relationship between man and ………….",
        "options": [
            "Notebook",
            "Environment",
            "During"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Does one require to obtain permission before deciding the date and time of the field trip ?",
        "options": [
            "Yes",
            "No"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Under whose supervision are the elections held in the country?",
        "options": [
            "The President",
            "The government",
            "The Election Commission of India",
            "The Prime Minister and his cabine"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true?",
        "options": [
            "Field visits help in understanding human-environment relationship.",
            "We should visit a river bank for understanding political features of a region.",
            "Field visits give us an opportunity to get first-hand information",
            "It is important to first understand the aim or purpose of a field visit."
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Is the first aid box should be taken during the field visit ? Yes / No",
        "options": [
            "Yes",
            "No"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Field trip provides …………… hand experience of geographical factors.",
        "options": [
            "First",
            "Second",
            "Third"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do you think a field trip is essential?",
        "options": [
            " It gives first-hand information about the landscape, economy, culture of natural surroundings.",
            "Helps us in understanding human-environment relationship.",
            "Enhance students learning.",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "A questionnaire helps to gather …………… about the place to be visited.",
        "options": [
            "Pictures",
            "Information",
            "People"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "True / False Environment should be taken care during the field trip",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following needs to be prepared after making a field trip?",
        "options": [
            "A Questionnaire",
            "Request latter to the concerned authorities for undertaking a field trip",
            "Report writing ",
            "Maps to find out the exact location of a place where the field visit has to be undertaken"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "True or False Camera is taken for field trip to click selfies",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the odd one : A note book, pen, pencil, googles, water bottle",
        "options": [
            "A note book",
            "Pen",
            "Pencil",
            "Googles"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "What should be ideally the first heading of the report writing while undertaking a trip to a government's office?",
        "options": [
            "Introduction",
            "Nature of the work in office",
            "Number of people employed in an office ",
            "Conclusion"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Report of the field trip is always written …………… the visit",
        "options": [
            "Before",
            "After",
            "During"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    }
]